{
  "heading": "Questions and Answers",
  "topics": [
    {
      "heading": "The Hound of the Baskervilles - Part 2 Questions",
      "questions": [
        {
          "questionNo": 1,
          "question": "What is the meaning of “Doddering”?",
          "options": [
            "Walking abnormally fast",
            "Walking briskly",
            "Moving in a feeble or unsteady way, especially because of old age",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "This question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 2,
          "question": "“He tried to stagger to his feet; but he was still ghastly pale and trembling in every limb.” Who is he in the above lines?",
          "options": [
            "Dr. Mortimer",
            "Frankland",
            "Lestrade",
            "Sir Henry"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "“You have saved my life.” “Having first endangered it. Are you strong enough to stand?” “Give me another mouthful of that brandy and I shall be ready for anything. So! Now, if you will help me up. What do you propose to do?” “To leave you here. You are not fit for further adventures tonight. If you will wait, one or other of us will go back with you to the Hall.” He tried to stagger to his feet; but he was still ghastly pale and trembling in every limb. We helped him to a rock, where he sat shivering with his face buried in his hands. “We must leave you now,” said Holmes. “The rest of our work must be done, and every moment is of importance. We have our case, and now we only want our man."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 3,
          "question": "A significant aspect of the atmospheric setting was the:",
          "options": [
            "Dark black sky of the night",
            "The moonlit sky",
            "The fog",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The entire story has repeated mentions of the fog. The difficulty that might arise due to the fog. The issues Holmes and his team faced because of the fog. The description of the fog being lit by the moonlight. Etc. Etc."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 4,
          "question": "Which chemical was used on the muzzle and body of the hound?",
          "options": [
            "Sulphur",
            "Phoric acid",
            "Phosphorous",
            "Calcium"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "I placed my hand upon the glowing muzzle, and as I held them up my own fingers smoldered and gleamed in the darkness. “Phosphorus,” I said. “A cunning preparation of it,” said Holmes, sniffing at the dead animal."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 5,
          "question": "What is the meaning of “Quagmire”?",
          "options": [
            "Marshy land",
            "A small barren island",
            "A soft boggy area of land that gives way underfoot",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "This question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 6,
          "question": "Where was Mrs. Stapleton locked?",
          "options": [
            "In the dining room of the Merripit House",
            "In one of the bedrooms upstairs in the Merripit House",
            "In the kitchen of the Merripit House",
            "In the outhouse of the Merripit House"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "On the upper floor, however, one of the bedroom doors was locked. “There’s someone in here,” cried Lestrade. “I can hear a movement. Open this door!” A faint moaning and rustling came from within…………….The room had been fashioned into a small museum, and the walls were lined by a number of glass-topped cases full of that collection of butterflies and moths the formation of which had been the relaxation of this complex and dangerous man. In the center of this room there was an upright beam, which had been placed at some period as a support for the old worm-eaten baulk of timber which spanned the roof. To this post a figure was tied, so swathed and muffled in the sheets which had been used to secure it that one could not for the moment tell whether it was that of a man or a woman. One towel passed round the throat and was secured at the back of the pillar. Another covered the lower part of the face, and over it two dark eyes—eyes full of grief and shame and a dreadful questioning—stared back at us."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 7,
          "question": "What is the author’s purpose behind describing the bedroom where Mrs. Stapleton was confined with such intricate details?",
          "options": [
            "Being a detective’s assistant Dr. Watson must have a keen eye for details specially because they are in the very room from which muffled noises had reached their ears",
            "Since it is the suspected criminal’s house, every detail is necessary for the investigation precisely because the details might work as clues",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 8,
          "question": "“Is he safe?” Who said these words and about whom?",
          "options": [
            "Mrs. Stapleton about Mr. Stapleton",
            "Mr. Holmes about Sir Henry",
            "Lestrade about Sir Henry",
            "Mrs. Stapleton about Sir Henry"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "“Is he safe?” she asked. “Has he escaped?” “He cannot escape us, madam.” “No, no, I did not mean my husband. Sir Henry? Is he safe?” “Yes.” “And the hound?” “It is dead.” She gave a long sigh of satisfaction."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 9,
          "question": "What is the meaning of the term ‘Atone’?",
          "options": [
            "Defend oneself",
            "Hide someone else’s mistakes",
            "Break confidentiality",
            "Make amends or reparation"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 10,
          "question": "‘Wrap in several layers of fabric’ can be termed as:",
          "options": [
            "Wrapped",
            "Covered",
            "Swathed",
            "Gnawed"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 11,
          "question": "What was Lestrade’s reaction on seeing the diabolical hound?",
          "options": [
            "Sprang to his feet",
            "Started forward in a rigid, fixed stare, and his lips parted in amazement.",
            "Gave a yell of terror and threw himself face downward upon the ground.",
            "Both A and B"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "At the same instant Lestrade gave a yell of terror and threw himself face downward upon the ground."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 12,
          "question": "Then Holmes and I both fired together, and the creature gave a hideous howl, which showed that one at least had hit him. Who is the ‘I’ in the above extract?",
          "options": [
            "Inspector Lestrade from Scotland Yard",
            "Sir Henry",
            "Dr. Watson",
            "Frankland"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "Dr. Watson is the first-person narrator of the story and that is why he is using the pronoun ‘I’ for himself."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 13,
          "question": "What was Sir Henry’s condition long after the confrontation with the Hound?",
          "options": [
            "He remained unconscious for two days at the Baskerville Hall",
            "He panicked because he had a nervous breakdown",
            "The shock of the night’s adventures had shattered his nerves, and before morning he lay delirious in a high fever under the care of Dr. Mortimer.",
            "All of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The shock of the night’s adventures had shattered his nerves, and before morning he lay delirious in a high fever under the care of Dr. Mortimer."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 14,
          "question": "“Go, rise, or improve faster than” is the meaning of:",
          "options": [
            "Hurl",
            "Dewlap",
            "Gaunt",
            "Outpaced"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 15,
          "question": "“In an acutely disturbed state of mind characterized by restlessness, illusions, and incoherence.” The above meaning is of:",
          "options": [
            "Conceived",
            "Exultant",
            "Crouching",
            "Delirious"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 16,
          "question": "The hound was compared to",
          "options": [
            "A pure blood hound",
            "A pure mastiff",
            "A small lioness",
            "None of the Above"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "In mere size and strength it was a terrible creature which was lying stretched before us. It was not a pure bloodhound and it was not a pure mastiff; but it appeared to be a combination of the two—gaunt, savage, and as large as a small lioness."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 17,
          "question": "………………………………had emptied five barrels of his revolver into the creature’s flank.",
          "options": [
            "Lestrade, the inspector from Scotland Yard",
            "Sir Charles Henry, the heir to the Baskerville estate",
            "Sherlock Holmes, the detective",
            "Dr. Watson, the assistant of Sherlock Holmes"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "But the next instant Holmes had emptied five barrels of his revolver into the creature’s flank."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 18,
          "question": "Sir Henry was wounded and was almost dead after the attack of the hound.",
          "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "But the next instant Holmes had emptied five barrels of his revolver into the creature’s flank. With a last howl of agony and a vicious snap in the air, it rolled upon its back, four feet pawing furiously, and then fell limp upon its side. I stooped, panting, and pressed my pistol to the dreadful, shimmering head, but it was useless to press the trigger. The giant hound was dead. Sir Henry lay insensible where he had fallen. We tore away his collar, and Holmes breathed a prayer of gratitude when we saw that there was no sign of a wound and that the rescue had been in time."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 19,
          "question": "What is the meaning of the word “appalling”?",
          "options": [
            "Terror",
            "Horrific",
            "Causing shock or dismay",
            "Both B and C"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "Appalling is an adjective which means those that is given in option B and C."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 20,
          "question": "Choose the correct option:",
          "options": [
            "The best evidence for the claim directly supports the assertion",
            "Comes from a source that is credible",
            "Is not purely anecdotal or based on the personal experiences of a single individual or a small number of people.",
            "All of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 21,
          "question": "A genre is a …………….. Or …………………….of art, music, or literature.",
          "options": [
            "Style",
            "Category",
            "Both A and B",
            "Type"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 22,
          "question": "Gothic fiction entails elements of:",
          "options": [
            "Horror",
            "Terror",
            "Bewildering suspense",
            "All of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 23,
          "question": "Opinions are something:",
          "options": [
            "A person believes, considers, or feels.",
            "They cannot be proved. Thus certain claims do not have any evidence.",
            "What conclusion do we draw from the above two statements?",
            "Certain claims do not have evidence",
            "All claims have evidence",
            "Some claims do not need evidence",
            "Both A and B"
          ],
          "answer": 6,
          "explanation": "Opinions are biased. They are based on subjective observations. So those claims which do not have any evidence and cannot be proved are opinions."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 24,
          "question": "What is the meaning of the word ‘Weal’?",
          "options": [
            "Boils on the skin",
            "Red patches on the skin",
            "A red, swollen mark left on the flesh by a blow or pressure.",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The question is self-explanatory."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 25,
          "question": "A fact cannot be verified by observation and research.",
          "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "A claim or opinion becomes a fact when it is proved by evidence. Evidence comes from observation or research."
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
